Arun Fnu

+1 (214) 699 6530

arunfnu0802@gmail.com

SUMMARY

IT Professional with 10+ years of Full Stack Development experience which includes 9 years of JavaScript framework experience and 4+ years of TypeScript experience. I have experience working with React, AWS, Docker and have 6 years of Node.JS experience. I also have 6 years of experience working within an agile CI/CD environment.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

<u>Walmart</u> Sunnyvale, CA (Remote) Lead Full Stack Developer (Jan 2021 - Present)

- Developed dynamic and responsive web pages using React, Redux, Bootstrap, Node.JS.
- JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, JSON, React JS, React Angular, Native, Redux, GraphQL.
- Configured REST API's using AWS Gateway, which triggers AWS Lambda to execute the business logic.
- Managed a team of 6 local software and firmware engineers and 6 outsourced engineers.
- Implemented a server-less architecture using API Gateway, Lambda and DynamoDB and deployed AWS Lambda code from Amazon S3 buckets.
- Involved in setting up the Cloud infrastructure using AWS Cloud formation and AWS Services.
- Implemented Lambda handlers for business logic and to execute cron jobs to import data.
- SVM to GITS migration. Defined Release cycle and communicated to all AD teams
- Wrote GraphQL schemas and async resolvers for MongoDB data manipulation, implemented back-end server with Apollo Express.
- Implemented real time functionalities with Apollo Client subscription methods.
- Working on Developing new application consists of front-end code written in JavaScript using Backbone, react that is similar to a REST API running on Node and front-end development using React.js.
- Development of single-page applications using React, Redux, HTML, NodeJS and SASS/LESS. Leveraged Redux for state management using Actions, Dispatchers, Providers and Store.
- Created visual presentations to the end user, using HTML5, JavaScript, React, Angular, Redux, ES6, TypeScript and ReactJS.
- Mainly, migrated JIRA, stash, confluence from physical lab production to open stack cloud.
- Upgraded all the plugins and applications (stash, Confluence, JIRA, Fisheye) and synced with the old production applications.
- Implemented analytics using Google Analytics and experience in creating website tags using Google Tag Manager.
- Created tags for Google Analytics using Google Tag Manager.
- Created ECMAScript reusable components and services to consume REST API's using Component based architecture.

- Experience in working with NoSQL databases like MongoDB, Cassandra, Graph DB (Neo4j).
- Experience in working with ECMAScript 6 features and Typescript like classes, interfaces etc.
- Responsible for creating web-based applications using JavaScript (ECMAScript 6), Spark,React JS
 ,Angular and Redux workflow.
- Developed web pages complying with Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) and ability to apply W3C standards.
- Implemented with security vulnerable fixes Cross Site Scripting (XSS), Cross Site Request Forgery (CSRF), Forceful Browsing, Request Token, Password Maintenance using OWASP framework.

<u>Canopy Health</u>, Emeryville, CA Remote Lead Full Stack Developer (March 2019 - Jan 2021)

- Developing dynamic web pages using HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, Angular 8/Angular10, Bootstrap, jQuery, D3JS, DCEJS, React.JS, Node.JS ES6,Spark, LESS, SASS.
- Designed and developed Restful API and services using best practices to interact within the Micro Services and with the front-end using Node, Express. Security is provided via tokens(JWT).
- Worked on React, Node, Typescript based application for Managing cloud configuration for Users.
- Worked on completely serverless architecture.
- Configured REST API's using AWS Gateway, which triggers AWS Lambda to execute the business logic.
- Managed a team of 6 local software and firmware engineers and 6 outsourced engineers.
- Implemented a server-less architecture using API Gateway, Lambda and DynamoDB and deployed AWS Lambda code from Amazon S3 buckets.
- Involved in setting up the Cloud infrastructure using AWS Cloud formation and AWS Services.
- Implemented Lambda handlers for business logic and to execute cron jobs to import data.
- Worked on implementing a new REST API and fixing bugs in existing API using Node.
- Implemented various screens for the frontend using ReactJS and used various predefined components from NPM (Node Package Manager) and redux library.
- Worked on various JavaScript libraries included but not limited to Node, Gulf, Grunt, npm, Bower, Karma, Jasmin.
- Worked with docker as an environment orchestration tool which helps setting up env easy.
- Designed Wireframes, Sitemaps, Mockups, Prototypes, Storyboards using Balsamiq.
- Developed components using story books to create packages and then utilising those components in the application to maintain the consistency.
- Created Typescript reusable components and services to consume REST API's using Component based architecture provided by React
- Created Custom Permission Levels, SharePoint User Groups and Custom Permissions for Lists.
- Involved in Agile software development life cycle (SDLC) with SCRUM methodology.
- Deployed developed code to all the environments.
- Worked on code cleanup using code quality tools like CSSLint, JSLint, and JSHint.
- Worked with GIT Version control.
- Worked with JEST for unit tests for the application

Environment: Angular8/10, Node, AWS, Typescript, EC2, ELB, Serverless, Spark, NodeJS, CloudFormation, VS Code

Wells Fargo, New York

Sr. Software Developer (July 2017 – March 2019)

- Worked on React, Node, Slim based application for Vehicle Pricing and Appraisal in which primary responsibilities include design and development of rate plan module for Online Account Management (OLAM).
- Developing a user interface application using HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Angular 8, JavaScript, Typescript, React ES6, Redux.
- Expertise in using React Component, Webhooks, Lifecycle methods.
- Created and Maintained HMVC Content Management System Website by using jQuery, JavaScript, HTML, CSS.
- Developed additional UI Components using JSF and implemented an asynchronous,
- AJAX (jQuery) based rich client to improve customer experience.
- Developed UI components for email and link sharing of documents and files for a Content Management System using Backbone.js and jQuery.
- Implemented Restful API using Node Express and CI to enable the partner's price estimations.
- Worked over Hybrid app development using PhoneGap and AngularJS.
- Involved in Agile software development life cycle (SDLC) with SCRUM methodology.
- Used JavaScript DOM manipulation and JavaScript event to generate the data result in UI.
- Implemented JWT token-based authentication for the REST API.
- Implemented API using Node Express to describe endpoints.
- Designed and implemented sharable and re-usable software service API's.
- Involved in site building and development of applications based on React, Node.
- Deployed developed code to all the environments.
- Worked closely with cross-functional teams (QA, BA, PM, Product Owner) as a part of AGILE environment.
- Maintenance of applications in all the environments.
- Experience with Front-end JavaScript frameworks like React, Node JS. And with the creation of RESTful Web service.
- Worked with GIT Version control.
- Worked with JEST for unit tests for the application

Environment: Node, HTML5/HTML, CSS3/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, JSON, PhoneGap, React, Express, Node.js, MVC, AJAX, VS Code,Spark, MongoDB, MySQL.

Accenture, Bengaluru, India Web Developer (Aug 2013 – Aug 2015)

- Developed Enterprise level applications using Java, Spring, Hibernate, Oracle, MVC Securities, Web Services and AJAX.
- Deployed Cloud platform on Amazon AWS using EC2, S3, SNS, auto scaling, SES, Cloud Watch and SQS.
- Worked with multiple SQL based database systems and DB platforms like Dynamo DB.
- Worked on Converting existing AWS Infrastructure to Serverless architecture (Lambda, Kinesis).

EDUCATION

- Bachelors of Engineering Computer Science-2013) from Rajiv Gandhi Technical University, Bhopal, India.
- Masters in Information Technology Management-2017, University of Potomac